<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cl:coverLetter xmlns:cl="http://ftn.uns.ac.rs/coverLetter">
    <cl:publicationTitle>Neural networks</cl:publicationTitle>
    <cl:author>
        <cl:name>Ziko Zikic</cl:name>
        <cl:educationTitle>phD</cl:educationTitle>
        <cl:affiliation>FTN</cl:affiliation>
        <cl:city>Novi Sad</cl:city>
        <cl:state>Serbia</cl:state>
        <cl:phoneNumber>23623483452345</cl:phoneNumber>
        <cl:email>ziko@dlsi.ua.es</cl:email>
        <cl:signature>ZGVmYXVsdA==</cl:signature>
    </cl:author>
    <cl:content>
        <cl:paragraph>
            <cl:boldText>Motivation</cl:boldText>
            <cl:emphasizedText>We believe that the problem to progress in OMR for CWMN lies in the complexity involved in
                correctly modeling the composition of musical symbols. Unlike these hand-engineered multi-stage
                approaches, we propose a holistic strategy in which the musical notation is learned as a whole using
                machine learning strategies. However, to reduce the complexity to a feasible level, we do consider
                a first initial stage in which the image is pre-processed to find and separate the different staves of the
                score. Staves are good basic units to work on, analogously to similar text recognition where a single
                line of text is assumed as input unit. Note that this is not a strong assumption as there are successful
                algorithms for isolating staves, as mentioned above.
            </cl:emphasizedText>
            <cl:quote>
                <cl:source>Kobe Bryant</cl:source>
                <cl:quoteContent>My parents are my backbone. Still are. They're the only group that will support you if you score zero or you score 40.</cl:quoteContent>
            </cl:quote>
            <cl:list ordered="true">
                <cl:listItem>Neural networks</cl:listItem>
                <cl:listItem>Machine Learning</cl:listItem>
                <cl:listItem>Deep Learning</cl:listItem>
            </cl:list>
            <cl:boldText>Motivation and about publication</cl:boldText>
            <cl:emphasizedText>We believe that the problem to progress in OMR for CWMN lies in the complexity involved in
                correctly modeling the composition of musical symbols. Unlike these hand-engineered multi-stage
                approaches, we propose a holistic strategy in which the musical notation is learned as a whole using
                machine learning strategies. However, to reduce the complexity to a feasible level, we do consider
                a first initial stage in which the image is pre-processed to find and separate the different staves of the
                score. Staves are good basic units to work on, analogously to similar text recognition where a single
                line of text is assumed as input unit. Note that this is not a strong assumption as there are successful
                algorithms for isolating staves, as mentioned above.
                Then, the staff can be addressed as a single unit instead of considering it as a sequence of isolated
                elements that have to be detected and recognized independently. This also opens the possibility
                to boost the optical recognition by taking into account the musical context which, in spite of being
                extremely difficult to model entirely, can certainly help in the process. Thus, it seems interesting to
                tackle the OMR task over single staves in an holistic fashion, in which the expected output is directly
                the sequence of musical symbols present in the image.</cl:emphasizedText>
            <cl:quote>
                <cl:source>Walt Whitman</cl:source>
                <cl:quoteContent>We convince by our presence.</cl:quoteContent>
            </cl:quote>
            <cl:list ordered="true">
                <listItem>Quantum AI</listItem>
                <listItem>Possibilities of new approaches</listItem>
                <listItem>AI and physics</listItem>
            </cl:list>
            <cl:boldText>Generalization and statistics</cl:boldText>
            <cl:emphasizedText>Applications whose goal is to create a system that generalizes well to unseen examples, face the possibility of over-training. This arises
                in convoluted or over-specified systems when the network capacity significantly exceeds the needed free parameters. Two approaches address over-training.
                The first is to use cross-validation and similar techniques to check for the presence of over-training and to select hyperparameters to minimize the
                generalization error.
                
                The second is to use some form of regularization. This concept emerges in a probabilistic (Bayesian) framework, where regularization can be performed by 
                selecting a larger prior probability over simpler models; but also in statistical learning theory, where the goal is to minimize over two quantities: the 
                'empirical risk' and the 'structural risk', which roughly corresponds to the error over the training set and the predicted error in unseen data due to
                overfitting.
                Supervised neural networks that use a mean squared error (MSE) cost function can use formal statistical methods to determine the confidence of the 
                trained model. The MSE on a validation set can be used as an estimate for variance. This value can then be used to calculate the confidence interval of
                network output, assuming a normal distribution. A confidence analysis made this way is statistically valid as long as the output probability distribution 
                stays the same and the network is not modified.
                
                By assigning a softmax activation function, a generalization of the logistic function, on the output layer of the neural network (or a softmax component 
                in a component-based network) for categorical target variables, the outputs can be interpreted as posterior probabilities. This is useful in classification
                as it gives a certainty measure on classifications.

            </cl:emphasizedText>
            <cl:quote>
                <cl:source>Lao Tzu</cl:source>
                <cl:quoteContent>Health is the greatest possession. Contentment is the greatest treasure. Confidence is the greatest friend. Non-being is the greatest joy.
                </cl:quoteContent>
            </cl:quote>
            <cl:list ordered="false">
                <cl:listItem>Hyperparameter</cl:listItem>
                <cl:listItem>Learning</cl:listItem>
                <cl:listItem>Learning rates</cl:listItem>
            </cl:list>
        </cl:paragraph>
        <cl:paragraph>
            <cl:boldText>Theory</cl:boldText>
            <cl:emphasizedText>A fundamental objection is that ANNs do not sufficiently reflect neuronal function. Backpropagation is a critical step, although no such 
                mechanism exists in biological neural networks.[118] How information is coded by real neurons is not known. Sensor neurons fire action potentials more
                frequently with sensor activation and muscle cells pull more strongly when their associated motor neurons receive action potentials more frequently.[119]
                Other than the case of relaying information from a sensor neuron to a motor neuron, almost nothing of the principles of how information is handled by 
                biological neural networks is known.
            </cl:emphasizedText>
            <cl:quote>
                <cl:source>Audrey Hepburn</cl:source>
                <cl:quoteContent>I believe in pink. I believe that laughing is the best calorie burner. I believe in kissing, kissing a lot. I believe in being strong
                    when everything seems to be going wrong. I believe that happy girls are the prettiest girls. I believe that tomorrow is another day and I believe 
                    in miracles.</cl:quoteContent>
            </cl:quote>
            <cl:list ordered="false">
                <listItem>RNN</listItem>
                <listItem>CNN</listItem>
                <listItem>LSTM</listItem>
            </cl:list>
            <cl:boldText>Hardware</cl:boldText>
            <cl:emphasizedText>Large and effective neural networks require considerable computing resources.[125] While the brain has hardware tailored to the task 
                of processing signals through a graph of neurons, simulating even a simplified neuron on von Neumann architecture may consume vast amounts of memory
                and storage. Furthermore, the designer often needs to transmit signals through many of these connections and their associated neurons – which require 
                enormous CPU power and time.
                
                Schmidhuber noted that the resurgence of neural networks in the twenty-first century is largely attributable to advances in hardware: from 1991 to 2015, 
                computing power, especially as delivered by GPGPUs (on GPUs), has increased around a million-fold, making the standard backpropagation algorithm feasible
                for training networks that are several layers deeper than before.[126] The use of accelerators such as FPGAs and GPUs can reduce training times from months 
                to days.[127][125]
                
                Neuromorphic engineering addresses the hardware difficulty directly, by constructing non-von-Neumann chips to directly implement neural networks in circuitry.
                Another type of chip optimized for neural network processing is called a Tensor Processing Unit, or TPU.[128]                
            </cl:emphasizedText>
            <cl:quote>
                <cl:source>Earl N.</cl:source>
                <cl:quoteContent>All you need is the plan, the road map, and the courage to press on to your destination.</cl:quoteContent>
            </cl:quote>
        </cl:paragraph>
        
        <cl:paragraph>
            <cl:boldText>Network design</cl:boldText>
            <cl:emphasizedText>Neural architecture search (NAS) uses machine learning to automate ANN design. Various approaches to NAS have designed networks that compare
                well with hand-designed systems. The basic search algorithm is to propose a candidate model, evaluate it against a dataset and use the results as feedback
                to teach the NAS network.[80] Available systems include AutoML and AutoKeras.[81]
                
                Design issues include deciding the number, type and connectedness of network layers, as well as the size of each and the connection type (full, pooling, ...).
                
                Hyperparameters must also be defined as part of the design (they are not learned), governing matters such as how many neurons are in each layer,
                learning rate, step, stride, depth, receptive field and padding (for CNNs), etc.[82]
                
            </cl:emphasizedText>
        </cl:paragraph>
    </cl:content>
</cl:coverLetter>
